Timothy Horsfield Papers 1684-1771 Mss.974.8.H78
American Philosophical Society
- Timothy Horsfield Papers, 1684-1771; 0.5 lin. feet (Box 1)
  - to William Parsons, July 10, 1756; 199; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Enclosing speech intended for Indians, and his intentions about provisions and ammunition
  - to the Commanding Officers of Each Company and Detachment in the First Battalion in the Pennsylvania Regiment, July 10, 1756; 201; 1p.; Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760
    Enclosing Governor's orders about absences
  - to William Parsons, July 10, 1756; 205; 1p.; Reynolds, George
    Insufficiency of arms and ammunition at Fort Allen
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 10, 1756; 207; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Acknowledging July 10, and approving his plans
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 11, 1756; 209; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Intentions of removing Indians from Bethlehem to Easton; the Proclamation for suspension of hostility is continued for thirty days longer
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 11, 1756; 217; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Original of no. 209
  - to William Parsons, July 11, 1756; 211; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Re: removing the Indians
  - to William Parsons, July 11, 1756; 215; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Desiring him to afford protection to an individual to get in harvest
  - to William Parsons, July 13, 1756; 219; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Respecting Indians
  - to W. Edwards, July 14, 1756; 221; 1p.; Reynolds, George
    Probable arrival of Indians at Fort Allen and of his going to meet Capt. Newcastle
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 14, 1756; 225; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Expressing difficulty about arranging Indians
  - to William Edmonds, July 15, 1756; 227; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Intentions of going to Bethlehem to confer about removal of Indians
  - Instructions to Conrad Weiser for the First Battalion of the Pennsylvania regiment, July 17, 1756; 167; 2p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Regulating the officers and soldiers absences, and ordering then, as guards to the harvest labourers
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 18, 1756; 229; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Arrival in Easton
  - Message to the Governor upon his arrival, July 18, 1756; 231; 1p.; Teedyuscung
  - to William Parsons, July 22, 1756; 233; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Changing the intention of meeting Indians and desiring detachments to be drawn in and sent to Bethlehem
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 22, 1756; 237; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Acknowledging intelligence communicated by King Teedyuscung approving of his having sent express and notifying change of place of meeting Indians
  - to William Parsons, July 22, 1756; 239; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Advising of Governor and suite going to Easton
  - to William Parsons, July 23, 1756; 241; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Stating intention of Governor
  - to William Parsons, July 23, 1756; 245; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Sending shirt for Ben
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 24, 1756; 247; 1p.; Barons, Benjamin
    Acknowledging his communication of Indian intelligence (no. 237)
  - Order to Conrad Weiser, July 30, 1756; 249; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    To hold a Court Martial for trial of two soldiers for sleeping on duty
  - Proceedings of Court Martial and acquittal of prisoners, July 30, 1756; 251; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 9, 1756; 255; 2p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Desiring an escort for Indians
  - letter to Timothy Horsfield and William Parsons, Aug. 9, 1756; 257; 1p.; Teedyuscung
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 11, 1756; 259; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
  - to King Teedyuscung, Aug. 12, 1756; 263; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    In answer to his of August 9th
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 12, 1756; 261; 1p.; Reynolds, George
    Concerning a shed for Indians and a guard in his absence
  - Substance of Capt. Widerhold's letter giving an account of disturbances at Fort Allen, Aug. 12, 1756; 253; 1p.; Widerhold, John Nicholus
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Aug. 13, 1756; 265; 2p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Complaining of Teedyuscung's delaying his journey so shamefully
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Aug. 13, 1756; 339; 1p.; Morris, Robert Hunter, 1713-1764
    Desiring Indians left by the King to be sent to Bethlehem
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 13, 1756; 267; 1p.; Orndt, Jacob
    Murder committed by the Indians on harvest guard
  - draft to Robert Hunter Morris, Aug. 14, 1756; 269; 2p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Re: Fort Allen and Teedyuscung
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 15, 1756; 271; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Enclosing Governor's letter
  - to Robert Hunter Morris, Aug. 15, 1756; 273; 3p., 2p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Re: disorders at Fort Allen (with duplicate)
  - To Timothy Horsfield(?), Aug. 19, 1756; 281; 1p.; Morgan, Jacob
    Fort Granville was taken by French and Indians
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 19, 1756; 283; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Concerning some bad designs he had heard of Indians
  - to Robert Hunter Morris, Aug. 21, 1756; 285; 2p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Re: Indians at Fort Allen
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 21, 1756; 288; 2p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Col. William Denny is appointed Governor
  - to Conrad Weiser, Aug. 21, 1756; 292; 2p.; Denny, William
    Concerning an intended attack upon Bethlehem and disorders at Fort Allen
  - to William Parsons, Aug. 22, 1756; 296; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Acknowledging letters
  - to William Parsons, Aug 24, 1756; 300; 2p.; Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760
    Requiring his attendance at Bethlehem
  - to Conrad Weiser, Aug. 24, 1756; 302; 2p.; Orndt, Jacob
    Re: conduct of Lt. Miller
  - to Benjamin Franklin, Aug. 25, 1756; 306; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Enclosing a bill of exchange of Mr. Nugent's
  - to Conrad Weiser, Aug. 26, 1756; 308; 1p.; Reynolds, George
    Complaining of attacks on his character
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Sept. 6, 1756; 312; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Thanks for attention to Indian affairs
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Sept. 6, 1756; 341; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Thanks for attention to Indian affairs (copy of no. 312)
  - to William Denny, Oct. 27, 1756; 314; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Concerning Indians
  - to Benjamin Franklin, Fox, et al., Nov. 29, 1756; 316; 2p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Dec. 2, 1756; 318; 1p.; Denny, William
    Acknowledging important intelligence, suggesting measures and providing arms
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Dec. 2, 1756; 345; 1p.; Denny, William
    Acknowledging important intelligence, suggesting measures and providing arms (copy of no. 318)
  - to August Gottlieb Spangenberg, Dec. 2, 1756; 343; 1p.; Denny, William
    Recommending him to receive Indians and Commissioners will pay necessary charges
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Dec. 9, 1756; 320; 1p.; Denny, William
    Advising of the grant of fifty stand of arms
  - Discription of the Nain and Wechquetane Indians from the wild Indians [sic], ca.1756; 525; 1p.
  - Indian intelligence, 1756; 322; 5p.
  - Passport for Joseph Peepy and Lewis Montour (friendly Indians), Jan. 9, 1757; 349; 1p.; Denny, William
  - to Benjamin Franklin, Fox, et al., Jan. 21, 1757; 351; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Arrival of Joseph Peepy and Lewis Montour; conduct of piety
  - to William Denny, Jan. 21, 1757; 353.; 2p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Feb. 20, 1757; 355.; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Probable arrival of Teedyuscung to the Governor
  - to William Parsons, Feb. 22, 1757; 357; 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    His account has not been settled by Commissioners; has been ordered to England; final settlement of disputes
  - to Richard Peters, Feb. 23, 1757; 359; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
  - to William Parsons, March 3, 1757; 361; 1p.; Snider, Jacob
    Re: conduct of Hieronymus Faxter and his discharge
  - to Timothy Horsfield, March 16, 1757; 363; 1p.; Chapman, John
  - Answer to Indians at Bethlehem, March 31, 1757; 365; 1p.; Denny, William
  - to Timothy Horsfield, March 31, 1757; 369; 1p.; Denny, William
    Enclosing preceding and alluding to military watch
  - Passport for Nathaniel (friendly Indian), April 4, 1757; 371; 1p.; Galbreath, James
  - to Timothy Horsfield, April 5, 1757; 330; 1p.; Denny, William
    Desiring guns and kettles to be repaired at expense of Commissioners
  - to unidentified, April 26, 1757; 373; 1p.; Denny, William
    Re: Indians going to Bethlehem
  - to Timothy Horsfield, April 26, 1757; 332; 1p.; Denny, William
    Desiring Indians to stay at Bethlehem till King comes
  - to Timothy Horsfield, April 28, 1757; 375; 2p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Re: Indian affairs
  - Message to the Delaware (Christian) Indians to attend at the Treaty at Lancaster, May 1, 1757; 377; 2p.; Jonathan, a Mohawk Sachem
  - Record of council with Delaware (Christian) Indians, May 1, 1757; 379; 2p.
  - to William Parsons, May 3, 1757; 381; 1p.; Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790
    Re: Nugent
  - to Timothy Horsfield, May 24, 1757; 383; 1p.; Croghan, George, d.1782
    Desiring to expedite two friendly Indians to Teedyuscung
  - to Timothy Horsfield, May 25, 1757; 385; 1p.; Trent, Capt.
    Re: preceding
  - to Timothy Horsfield, May 26, 1757; 387; 1p.; Read, James, 1718-1793
  - to Timothy Horsfield, June 6, 1757; 391; 1p.; Denny, William
    Re: ammunition
  - to Timothy Horsfield, June 13, 1757; 393; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
    Re: raising men
  - to Timothy Horsfield, June 19, 1757; 395; 1p.; Parsons, William, 1701-1757
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 7, 1757; 397; 1p.; Denny, William
    Acknowledging receipt of letters of Teedyuscung
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 9, 1757; 399; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Re: an Indian being shot through the thigh by a white boy, and desiring his apprehension
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Sept. 5, 1757; 401; 1p.; Denny, William
  - to William Denny, Oct. 6, 1757; 405; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Re Teedyuscung and his going to Philadelphia
  - to William Parsons, Oct. 23, 1757; 407; 1p.; Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760
    Enclosing money
  - to William Denny, Nov. 2, 1757; 411; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    Re: Teedyuscung
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Jan. 16, 1758; 413; 1p.; Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760
    Resigning commission as Lt.-Col.; attack of palsy
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Feb. 3, 1758; 417; 1p.; Denny, William
    Enclosing letters for Captains and recommending Mr. Swaine
  - to Timothy Horsfield, April 14, 1758; 421; 1p.; Strettell, Robert
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Jan. 17, 1761; 425; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Re: discharge of garrison at Fort Allen
  - Account of Ammunition, Stores etc. in Fort Allen, Jan. 21, 1761; 427; 2p.
    Jan. 17
  - to James Hamilton, July 22, 1761; 431; 1p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Aug. 29, 1761; 433; 2p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Desiring information on Indian affairs
  - Affidavit respecting Indians, Sept. 2, 1761; 437; 3p.; Brodhead, Charles
  - to James Hamilton in reply to Aug. 29, Sept. 3, 1761; 441; 4p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
  - to James Hamilton, Sept. 5, 1761; 445; 2p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
    With additional information
  - to Timothy Horsfield, March 11, 1762; 447; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
    Enclosing letters for Teedyuscung
  - to Timothy Horsfield, May 7, 1762; 449; 1p.; Peters, Richard, 1743-1828
  - to Timothy Horsfield, June 23, 1763; 451; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Requesting, intelligence on Indian affairs
  - to James Hamilton, June 27, 1762; 455; 2p.; Horsfield, Timothy, 1708-1773
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 11, 1763; 456; 2p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Authorizing Horsfield to raise two Companies of Foot
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 11, 1763; 458; 2p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Recruiting instructions
  - Commission for Timothy Horsfield as Commander of the Companies of Foot from Northampton County, July 11, 1763; 460; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 26, 1763; 463; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Reposing confidence in his nomination of officers
  - to Timothy Horsfield, July 27, 1763; 467; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Re: additional force at Easton
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Aug. 13, 1763; 471; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Acknowledging communications; enclosing £100 and expressing great satisfaction at his proceedings
  - Petition to James Hamilton, Aug. 17, 1763; 475; 2p.; Upper Smithfield Township (Pa.). Inhabitants.
    Requesting men to range and scour the woods
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Aug. 19, 1763; 479; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Re: an associated independent company at Mt. Bethel
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Sept. 1, 1763; 483; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Acknowledging satisfaction at his Journal of proceedings
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Sept. 20, 1763; 487; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Indian affairs
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Oct. 10, 1763; 491; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Oct. 13, 1763; 495; 1p.; Shippen, Joseph
    Enclosing letters for express delivery
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Oct. 13, 1763; 499; 1p.; Hamilton, James, 1710-1783
    Desiring his attendance at Pennsylvania with testimony in favor of Moravian Indians
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Oct. 13, 1763; 503; 2p.; Grube, Bernard Adam
  - to Timothy Horsfield, Nov. 14, 1763; 506; 1p.; Penn, John, 1729-1795
    Appointing Major Clayton to succeed to command of Companies
  - to Timothy Horsfield et al., Nov. 23, 1771; 509; 1p.; Penn, Richard
    Desiring inquiry to be made respecting Elizabeth Kortsey
  - to Timothy Horsfield, n.d.; 513; 1p.; Weiser, Conrad, 1696-1760
    Enclosing letters for delivery to Officers in command of forts
  - Address to Kolapeeha and the other Indians, 517; 2p.
  - n.d., 519; 1p.; Busse, Christian
    Account of scalping of the Felix Wins and capture of his wife and children
  - Petition to the Governor of Pennsylvania, n.d.; 527; 2p.; Indians at Bethlehem and Wampaqueca (Wyoming).
  - Sermon concerning friendly and enemy Indians, 535; 8p.